<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vincent Thiery</title>
    <link>https://vthiery.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vincent Thiery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vthiery.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Learning Resources</title>
      <link>https://vthiery.github.io/notes/learning-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vthiery.github.io/notes/learning-resources/</guid>
      <description>A list of resources that I use to teach myself cybersecurity and recommend.
Malware Analysis / Reverse Engineering Online courses  Zero2Automated - Advanced Malware Analysis - In progress OpenSecurityTraining2  Reverse Engineering 3201: Symbolic Analysis - July 2023 Reverse Engineering 3011: Reversing C++ Binaries - July 2023 Architecture 1001: x86-64 Assembly - July 2023   Sektor7  RED TEAM Operator: Malware Development Intermediate - May 2023 RED TEAM Operator: Malware Development Essentials - April 2023   TCM Security - Practical Malware Analysis &amp;amp; Triage - February 2023  Books  Practical Malware Analysis by Michael Sikorski and Andrew Honig  General Online courses  Udemy - Chris Greer&amp;rsquo;s Wireshark Hands-On Course - May 2023 TCM Security  Python 201 for Hackers - May 2023 OSINT Fundamentals - March 2023 Practical Windows Forensics - March 2023   HTB Academy - Bug Bounty Hunter role path - January 2023  Books  Practical Threat Intelligence and Data-Driven Threat Hunting by Valentina Costa-Gazcón Huntpedia Intelligence-Driven Incident Response by Rebekah Brown, Scott J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering the &#34;Bomb Lab&#34; with Cutter</title>
      <link>https://vthiery.github.io/posts/2023/07/reverse-engineering-the-bomb-lab-with-cutter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vthiery.github.io/posts/2023/07/reverse-engineering-the-bomb-lab-with-cutter/</guid>
      <description>Context I recently took the excellent &amp;ldquo;Architecture 1001: x86-64 Assembly&amp;rdquo; course offered by Xeno Kovah on OpenSecurityTraining2 to consolidate my knowledge of x86-64 assembly. The final assignment consists in solving the &amp;ldquo;Bomb Lab&amp;rdquo;.
Although the course suggests to use gdb or WinDbg, I decided to do it differently and use Cutter with the following constraints:
 Not using debug symbols - this is something Xeno actually recommends if one has some reverse-engineering experience, or want extra challenge Perform a pure static analysis - using gdb/gef would be much smarter here, but I really wanted to practice static analysis Not using rz-ghidra or any decompiler since that would defeat the whole point of the exercise  I used Cutter Version 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forensic Lab setup with REMnux &#43; Sift &#43; FlareVM</title>
      <link>https://vthiery.github.io/posts/2023/03/forensic-lab-setup-with-remnux--sift--flarevm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vthiery.github.io/posts/2023/03/forensic-lab-setup-with-remnux--sift--flarevm/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will guide you through the setup of a Forensic lab using:
 VirtualBox 7 REMnux + Sift on Ubuntu 20.04 FlareVM on Windows 10  It is mostly a summary of notes I took while building my own lab.
Disclaimer Do not follow this guide blindly!
Be very careful during the setup of your forensic lab, especially if you intend to manipulate and/or detonate malware. I am in no way responsible for any harm or damage you may cause and you should always make sure you are operating in a safe environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vincent Thiery</title>
      <link>https://vthiery.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vthiery.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR  I am currently working as CISO for Edgelab / Evooq in Switzerland. Also worked as SRE (2y), Software Engineer (3y+), and Quant (2y+). Before that, I studied maths, physics, and quantitative finance. I&amp;rsquo;m curious, enjoy learning new things, and passionate about cybersecurity. I speak French and English. Feel free to contact me by email.  Experiences &amp;mdash; Chief Information Security Officer (CISO) @ Edgelab / Evooq Since Sep 2021</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
