<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Vincent Thiery</title>
    <link>https://vthiery.github.io/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Vincent Thiery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vthiery.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Learning Resources</title>
      <link>https://vthiery.github.io/notes/learning-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vthiery.github.io/notes/learning-resources/</guid>
      <description>A list of resources I use to teach myself cybersecurity and recommend.
Courses  Zero2Automated - Advanced Malware Analysis - In progress Udemy - Chris Greer&amp;rsquo;s Wireshark Hands-On Course - May 2023 Sektor7 - RED TEAM Operator: Malware Development Intermediate - May 2023 TCM Security - Python 201 for Hackers - May 2023 Sektor7 - RED TEAM Operator: Malware Development Essentials - April 2023 TCM Security - OSINT Fundamentals - March 2023 TCM Security - Practical Windows Forensics - March 2023 TCM Security - Practical Malware Analysis &amp;amp; Triage - February 2023 HTB Academy - Bug Bounty Hunter role path - January 2023  CTFs and Labs  CyberSoc CyberDefenders Hack The Box HTB Academy PortSwigger Academy  Books  Practical Threat Intelligence and Data-Driven Threat Hunting by Valentina Costa-Gazcón Huntpedia Intelligence-Driven Incident Response by Rebekah Brown, Scott J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forensic Lab setup</title>
      <link>https://vthiery.github.io/notes/forensic-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vthiery.github.io/notes/forensic-lab/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will guide you through the setup of a Forensic lab using:
 VirtualBox 7 REMnux + Sift on Ubuntu 20.04 FlareVM on Windows 10  It is mostly a summary of notes I took while building my own lab.
Disclaimer Do not follow this guide blindly!
Be very careful during the setup of your forensic lab, especially if you intend to manipulate and/or detonate malware. I am in no way responsible for any harm or damage you may cause and you should always make sure you are operating in a safe environment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
